{"test_questions": [[{"question": "HIV can infect", "opta": "Microglial cells", "optb": "M (membranous) cells", "optc": "CD4 + T lymphocytes", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Parasitic infection/s frequently observed in HIV disease is / are.", "opta": "cryptosporidiosis", "optb": "toxoplasmosis", "optc": "isosporiasis", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the average incubation period for development of AIDS?", "opta": "One year", "optb": "Five years", "optc": "Ten years", "optd": "Twenty years", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The commonest bacterial infection in HIV disease is/are", "opta": "mycobacterial infection", "optb": "salmonella infection", "optc": "bartonella infection", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Viral infections frequently observed in HIV disease is /are", "opta": "herpes simplex", "optb": "varicella- zoster", "optc": "cytomegalo virus", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The commonest opportunistic infection in AIDS patient in India is", "opta": "cryptosporidiosis", "optb": "toxoplasmosis", "optc": "tuberculosis", "optd": "cryptococcosis", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "HIV belongs to the family retroviridae and sub-family", "opta": "Oncovirinae", "optb": "Lentivirinae", "optc": "Spumavirinae", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "HIV or Human Immunodeficiency Virus is considered unique because each virus contains:", "opta": "more than 100 copies of the viral genome", "optb": "a genome made up of both DNA and RNA components", "optc": "a viral enzyme known as reverse transcriptase", "optd": "sticky proteins that allow it to bind tightly to host cells", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is transmembrane pedicle antigen of HIV-I?", "opta": "gp 41", "optb": "gp 140", "optc": "gp l20", "optd": "gp 36", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The confirmatory test(s) for HIV infection is/are", "opta": "virus isolation", "optb": "detection of p24 antigen", "optc": "detection of viral nucleic acid", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A viral load test detects the", "opta": "provirus of HIV in infected cells", "optb": "total amount of virus in the infected host", "optc": "number of viruses being released by each infected cell", "optd": "amount of bacteriophage being produced by E. coli cells", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fungal infection/s frequently observed in HIV disease is /are:", "opta": "candidiasis", "optb": "cryptococcosis", "optc": "aspergillosis", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The screening test/s for diagnosis of HIV infection is/are", "opta": "ELISA", "optb": "Latex agglutination", "optc": "Dot blot assay", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The problem(s) associated with development of a vaccine against HIV is/are", "opta": "antibody alone may be insufficient", "optb": "rapid mutation of HIV", "optc": "virus can spread from cell to cell by fusion to produce syncytia", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The commonest mode of transmission of HIV is", "opta": "parenteral", "optb": "perintal", "optc": "sexual", "optd": "oral", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cells most oftenly infected by HIV are", "opta": "Null cells", "optb": "CD8 + T lymphocytes", "optc": "CD4 + T lymphocytes", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the spike antigen of HIV-I?", "opta": "gp 120", "optb": "gp 140", "optc": "gp 36", "optd": "gp 41", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}